《歡樂合唱團》前情提要
So here's what you missed on Glee:
蕾切爾和桑塔納鬧不和
Rachel and Santana are on the outs
因為桑塔納當上了《妙女郎》里蕾切爾的替角
because Santana landed a job in Funny Girl as Rachel's understudy,
盡管桑塔納是拉丁人  而范妮·布萊斯是猶太人
even though Santana's Latin and Fanny Brice is clearly Jewish.
我們從來都不是朋友
You and I have never been friends.
以前不是  將來也不是
Never have and never will be.
全國賽即將來臨  畢業典禮兩周后舉行
Nationals is fast approaching and graduation's in two weeks.
-畢業生同學們  -天  這不可能
- My fellow graduates. - God, this can't be happening.
但并非所有人都知道他們畢業之后何去何從
But not everyone knows what they're going to do once they graduate,
因為新航向成員們的生活規劃
because New Directions! seem to plan their lives
基本上和他們選歌一樣
like they plan their set lists--
不拖到最后一刻不舒服
they pretty much figure it out the night before.
我還沒決定好
I'm not ready to make a decision yet.
好吧
Okay.
這就是《歡樂合唱團》前情回顧
And that's what you missed on Glee.
他們要走蘭斯福德·哈斯廷斯發現的捷徑
They were encouraged to take the shortcut by Lansford Hastings,
那條路從來沒有馬車走過
who had never taken the journey with wagons.
這樣他們就要穿過猶他州的瓦薩奇山
This required them to traverse through Utah's Wasatch Mountains...
威爾  到點了  現在開始
Will, it's time. We have to do it right now.
冬天來了  "當納聚會"成員被困在山里
Winter came and the Donner Party got trapped in the mountains
前往加利福尼亞淘金的一次死亡之旅  87名成員中死亡40人
他們靠吃同伴活命  大家討論
and they ate each other-- everybody discuss.
你好啊  今天怎樣  不錯嗎  好
What's up, buddy? How you doing? All right, cool.
職工廁所
里面是怎么了
What's going on in there?
我渾身上下都不舒服
I am disturbed on every level.
貝基的心理陰影一輩子都抹不掉了
And Becky has been scarred for life.
蘇  我太丟臉了
Sue, I'm mortified.
我們非常  非常
We are so, so...
我知道你有洞有毛的骨盆下
I am aware that the pheromones emitted from the orifices
會釋放出一些外激素
of your porous, bird-lady pelvis
讓你產生與某位情緒激動
can cause an overwhelming urge to copulate
屁股下巴  跟青少年為伍
in some emotionally stunted man-children,
不會說唱的老男孩交配的強烈欲望
with butt-chins, who befriend teenagers and can't rap.
但怎么就不能等回到
But why could you not wait to copulate until you returned
你們甜到發膩的溫柔鄉再交配呢
to the sickly-sweet stench of your own conjugal bed?
我  呃  蘇
I'm... well, Sue, uh...
威爾和我打算懷孩子
Will and I are trying to conceive a child...
天啊  為啥
Oh, God, why?
在特定的時間段內
...and-and there are certain windows of time
受精成功的幾率會比較高
where fertilization is most likely.
我們覺得現在有了不錯的經濟基礎
See, we-we finally feel like we have some financial security;
我37歲
I'm 37...
嗯  我也和他差不多大
Yes, and I'm-I'm... I'm of a similar age range,
過了35歲之后
and after the age of 35,
懷上有先天缺陷的孩子幾率會大大提高
you know, the chances of birth defects increase dramatically.
有脆性X染色體綜合征
There's, um, fragile X chromosome,
唐氏綜合癥
there's Down syndrome...
-唐氏綜合癥怎么了  -唐氏綜合癥怎么了
- What's wrong with Down syndrome? - What's wrong with Down syndrome?
-沒什么  只是  -不是  蘇
- N-No... nothing. There's... That's... - No. N... No, Sue...
蘇  我們很抱歉
Look, Sue, we are so sorry.
我保證下不為例
This is not gonna happen again, I promise.
希望不用再有下次  如果我能趕緊
Well, hopefully it won't have to, if I hurry up right now
躺在辦公室地板  腳抬高放椅子上
and lie down on the floor in my office and put my feet up on a chair,
因為他剛才成功射精了
because we were able to achieve a successful emission.
夠了  趕緊出去
Okay, get the hell out of my office.
謝謝合作
Please. Thanks.
不要告訴我啊
Oh, didn't need to know that.
我不想知道細節  不要
Didn't need to know that. Nope.
歡樂合唱團
第五季 第十集
對話翻譯：free維塔  某豚  包子萌豹子  餓得慌
*姑娘們把漢子留在家里吧*
*Ladies leave yo man at home*
*夜店滿是花花公子  土豪又多金*
*The club is full of ballas and they pockets full grown*
歌詞翻譯：某豚  爵士年代蓬蓬裙  萌su  肉松  麥克杜格  餓得慌
*伙計們放媳婦跟閨蜜玩去吧*
*And all you fellas leave yo girl with her friends*
*只因現在是午夜時分  夜店里嗨到爆*
*'Cause it's 11:30 and the club is jumpin' jumpin'*
時間軸：餓得慌  沒有影子    校對&后期&總監：餓得慌
*雖說鴛有鴦  鳳配凰*
*Boys say you got a girl? Yes true you got a man*
*但狂歡不會就此停歇  快來炒熱氣氛*
*But the party ain't gonna stop so let's make it hot hot!*
*上周你獨自在家  孤苦伶仃*
*Last week and you stayed at home alone and lonely*
*男友不見蹤影  跟哥們廝混*
*Couldn't find yo man he was chillin' with his homies*
*這周換你  出門尋歡*
*This week and your goin' out if he*
*他若不許  你就大鬧*
*Try to stop you your goin' off*
*美發美甲  一樣不少*
*You got ya hair done and ya nails done too*
*精挑靚裝  細選美鞋*
*And your outfit and your fittin' the shoes*
*奔赴最熱的夜場作樂*
*Who parlayin' at the hottest spot tonight you're gonna*
*看到小伙們開著豪車*
*find the fellas rollin' in the lexus, trucks and hummers*
*雖說鴛有鴦  鳳配凰*
*Boys say you got a girl? Yes true you got a man*
*但狂歡不會就此停歇  快來炒熱氣氛*
*But the party ain't gonna stop so let's make it hot hot!*
*姑娘們把漢子留在家里吧*
*Ladies leave yo man at home*
*夜店滿是花花公子  土豪又多金*
*The club is full of ballas and they pockets full grown*
*伙計們放媳婦跟閨蜜玩去吧*
*And all you fellas leave yo girl with her friends*
*只因現在是午夜時分  夜店里嗨到爆*
*'Cause it's 11:30 and the club is jumpin' jumpin'*
*姑娘們把漢子留在家里吧*
*Ladies leave yo man at home*
*夜店滿是花花公子  土豪又多金*
*The club is full of ballas and they pockets full grown*
*伙計們放媳婦跟閨蜜玩去吧*
*And all you fellas leave yo girl with her friends*
*只因現在是午夜時分  夜店里嗨到爆*
*'Cause it's 11:30 and the club is jumpin' jumpin'*
*性感小妞舞起來  型男坐等挑逗*
*Sexy women do your dance fly ladies work yo man*
*輪到小伙們上場  我們盡情狂歡*
*All them fellas time to clown we can get down now*
*跟我跳啊  跳跳跳  電臀扭啊扭*
*Bounce with me, bounce bounce bounce twirk it twirk it*
*搖擺吧寶貝  搖搖搖*
*Shake baby shake shake shake work it work it*
*翹臀扭起來  深蹲才過癮*
*Twist baby twist twist twist you better dip that thang*
*深蹲才過癮*
*Better dip that thang...*
*跟我跳啊  跳跳跳  電臀扭啊扭*
*Bounce with me, bounce bounce bounce twirk it twirk it*
*搖擺吧寶貝  搖搖搖*
*Shake baby shake shake shake (Shaake it!) work it work it*
*扭吧寶貝  扭扭扭*
*Twist (Twist it) baby twist twist (Twist it) twist *
*深蹲才過癮*
*You better dip that thang (Dip that thang)*
*雖說鴛有鴦  鳳配凰*
*Boys say you got a girl? Yes true you got a man*
*但狂歡不會就此停歇  快來炒熱氣氛*
*But the party ain't gonna stop so let's make it hot hot! *
*姑娘們把漢子留在家里吧*
*Ladies leave yo man at home*
*夜店滿是花花公子  土豪又多金*
*The club is full of ballas and they pockets full grown *
*伙計們放媳婦跟閨蜜玩去吧*
*And all you fellas leave yo girl with her friends*
*只因現在是午夜時分  夜店里嗨到爆*
*'Cause it's 11:30 and the club is jumpin' jumpin'*
為大家而唱
Doin' it for the people.
大伙兒唱得很棒  但是
You guys, that was amazing, but, um,
我覺得這歌不適合在全國賽上唱
I'm not sure it's right for Nationals.
對  因為"獨一"不會當人肉背景搖啊搖
Yes, 'cause Unique will not be standing in the back swaying
風頭全讓你們又跑又跳搶光了
while you guys go all Three-yoncee in the spotlight.
為什么你說的每一句話都是這種調調
Why does everything you say have to sound like that?
我們知道不適合全國賽
We know it's not right for Nationals,
只是想唱著玩
we just wanted to do it for fun.
我們聊天的時候突然意識到
Yeah, we were talking and we realized that
我們三個還沒一起合唱過
we'd never actually done a number together.
對  我們是高四生
No, and as seniors we...
大家離畢業都不遠了
realized we were running out of time
我們想感受下三重唱的能量
and we wanted to feel the power of a trio.
我上高等數學的時候學到
Which, I learned in my senior math class,
三重唱比四重唱的威力少百分之二十五
is about 25% less powerful than a quartet.
我很高興你們能合唱這首歌
Well, I'm really glad that you guys did that.
你們或許沒意識到  但是這種友情
You probably don't realize this, but these are friendships
是你們可以珍藏一輩子的
that you're gonna cherish for the rest of your lives.
你們要盡可能多嘗試多體驗
And you've got to squeeze in as many experiences as you can
因為你們畢業生
because, for you seniors,
馬上就要分道揚鑣  各奔前程了
you're all gonna be going your separate ways very soon.
不要不要
Oh, no, no, no, no.
-別哭  別哭  -蒂娜  別哭
- No, no, no, no... - Tina, don't, no, no, no.
-不要這樣  -別哭  不用哭的
- No, no, no, no. - Stop, don't... you don't have to cry,
別哭  不用哭的  沒事
No. No! You don't have to cry. It's okay.
我們在  我們都在你身邊
We're here. We're here for you.
蒂娜  伙伴們
Tina. Guys.
你還好吧
You okay? Huh?
你以前已經抱過了
No, you had your turn.
-我會想念你們的  -沒事
- I'm gonna miss you guys. - That's okay.
好  我想先練序幕
Okay. So I want to start at the overture,
然后從頭至尾把整部劇目演下來
and then I want to do the entire show from top to bottom.
大概兩三次吧
Maybe two or three times.
天啊  艾略特  進來吧
Oh, my God, Elliot, hi. Come on in.
對不起
Sorry, uh,
你說要趁放假排練的時候
when you said you were gonna be rehearsing on your day off,
我還以為只有你一個人練聲
I assumed it would just be you, running scales.
既然小吉娜·葛森跟著我不放
Well, you know. Since I have Gina Gershon, Jr. nipping at my heels here,
我只得讓我的導演魯伯特去問制片人西德尼
I had to have Rupert, my director, ask Sidney, my producer,
我能不能雇一支全職樂隊 這樣就能盡情高歌
if I could have a full band on retainer at all times, so I could sing full voice,
保持嗓音的極佳狀態
just to keep my instrument really sharp.
你還有自己的樂隊  真不錯啊
Wow, you have your own band. That's impressive.
你可以隨時借用
Oh, yeah, you can borrow them anytime you want.
謝了
Thanks.
與此同時
Um, in the meanwhile,
我幫你把排練的衣服干洗過了
I got your rehearsal clothes dry-cleaned.
綠茶加蜜糖和檸檬
Green tea with honey and lemon,
還幫你配了把我公寓的鑰匙
and I got you your very own key to my apartment.
艾略特
Elliott!
說真的  如果你當時不讓我進門
Seriously, what would I have done
我該怎么辦啊
if you'd have turned me away at your door?
我當時像是田納西·威廉斯戲劇里的迷失女主角
I was like some heroine from a lost Tennessee Williams play.
[二十世紀最重要的劇作家之一  代表作《熱鐵皮屋頂上的貓》]
來了
Coming.
他們把我趕出來了
They kicked me out.
我沒地方可去
Hmm? I had nowhere else to go.
然后你很有紳士風度地
Then it was so chivalrous of you
幫我鋪好沙發
when you made up your couch for me.
但當我跟你描述我上周的悲慘經歷
but then gave me your bed, instead, when I explained
說一張凹凸不平的沙發
that after last week's traumatic events,
無法撫慰我受傷的心靈之后
the only way I could recover is by sleeping in a real bed
你還是把床讓給了我
and not some lumpy surrogate.
所以你真的愿意無限期地和我一起住嗎
So you're sure you're okay with me living with you, like, indefinitely?
行啊沒問題  就像我說的
Yeah, it's cool. I mean, like I said,
租金太貴
my rent is so high,
我也一直在找室友
and I've been looking for a roommate,
-還有  -你現在有室友了
- and... - And now you have one.
我也有了新的好基友
And I have a new best gay.
是啊
Uh... Yeah, yeah.
我不太喜歡這個詞  感覺像形容寵物
I kind of hate that term. It makes me feel like a pet.
怎么了  很好玩啊
What do you mean? It's so funny.
你過去24小時內為我做的事
You have done more for me in the past 24 hours
比那叛徒科特·哈梅爾畢業后做的加起來還多
than that traitor Kurt Hummel has since graduation.
我剛準備唱整部《妙女郎》
I was just gonna sing the entire Funny Girl score.
你想看嗎
Do you want to watch?
好嘛  很好玩的
Oh, please, it'll be so fun--
-你愿意的話可以唱副歌  -這個我喜歡
- You can sing all the chorus parts, if you want. - Tempting.
我真的想跟你合唱
And I do want to sing with you,
不過不如來首偏搖滾的
but how about something a little more rock and roll?
本來打算讓帕米拉·蘭斯伯里唱的
I was gonna suggest this for Pamela Lansbury,
但也許你和我可以試試
but maybe you and I should give it a try.
我認為這是一段美好友誼的開端
I think this is the beginning of a beautiful, beautiful friendship.
下音樂
Hit it.
*一切尚未結束  你我今日又見*
*So this ain't the end, I saw you again today*
*我要將內心抽離*
*I had to turn my heart away, eeh*
*笑容陽光般燦爛  致每人甜吻*
*Smiled like the sun, kisses for everyone*
*傳奇永不滅*
*And tales, it never fails, alright!*
*你深躺野草中*
*You lying so low into the weeds*
*必定要埋伏我*
*Yeah, bet you wanna ambush me *
*你令我卑躬屈膝  跪倒在地*
*You have me down, down, down, down on my knees*
*對吧  梭子魚*
*Now, wouldn't you, Barracuda?*
■
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為
*回想當初  我們都追尋自由*
*Back over time we were all trying for free*
*你邂逅海豚與我*
*You met up with porpoise and me*
*無是無非  出賣一首歌一個名*
*No right no wrong, selling a song, a name*
*低聲傳話*
*Whisper game*
*如果真實不耍花招*
*And if the real thing don't do the trick*
*你最好趕緊計上心頭*
*You better make up something quick*
*你絞盡腦汁  燭芯燃盡*
*You gonna burn, burn, burn, burn into the wick*
*梭子魚*  *梭子魚*
*Ooh, Barra-Barracuda* *Barra-barracuda!*
*梭子魚*
*Barracuda!*
*Barracuda*
*梭子魚*
*Barracuda!*
真棒
All right.
我們得試試合不合身
We have to try them on to see if they fit.
小中大號  沒那么復雜好嗎
Small, medium, large, it's not that complicated, okay?
肯定都合身
I'm sure they all fit.
我們該穿上看看是什么樣子
Well, we should just try them on to see what they look like.
老天爺  真不敢相信畢業就近在眼前
Holy crap, I can't believe this is actually happening.
伙計們  怎么...
Hey, guys. What's...?
蒂娜  別哭別哭
Tina... Oh, no, no, ,no No, please d...
不要  蒂娜  別哭
No, no, Tina, Tina, no, no.
我知道你很難接受  可是別這樣嘛
I know this is hard for you, but come on, please.
別哭  不要哭
No, don't... don't cry. Try not to cry.
我還沒準備好跟你們道別
I'm not ready to say good-bye to you guys yet.
這不是道別
Well, it's not good-bye.
他們管畢業叫"畢業典禮[開始]"
They call graduation "commencement"
因為這不是結束  而是開端
because it's not the end of something, it's the beginning.
你這么說是為了讓我們心甘情愿地畢業
You say that so we'll go willingly.
薩姆  你和麥克之前很親近
Sam, you and Mike were so close.
帕克也是  你上次跟他們聊天是什么時候
Puck, too. When was the last time you talked to them?
我不知道
I-I don't know.
不記得了
I can't remember.
蕾切爾和我有好幾月沒打電話了
Rachel and I haven't spoken on the phone in months.
沒錯  我知道我們彼此友愛
And yes, I know we all love each other,
但維系高中友誼的紐帶
but the fact is the glue that holds high school friendships together
就是高中本身
is high school.
每天相互陪伴
Being around each other every day,
在走廊見面
seeing each other in the halls.
無論什么時候出了事
Whenever something is up,
我們不必想方設法去找朋友聊天
we don't have to do any work to talk to our friends about it,
他們就近在眼前
they're right there.
一旦交流要費勁了  我們就會變懶
As soon as it takes effort, we get lazy
忘記彼此  拋卻過往
and then we forget and then we just move on.
我不想從你們的生活中淡出
I don't want to fade away.
但其實事情可以不這么發展的
But it doesn't have to go down like that, though.
我爸最好的朋友仍然是他的高中好友
Like, my dad's best friends are still his high school buddies.
他們可以一年不聯系
And they can go, like, a year without talking to each other
再聚首時仍然心意相通
and they get together and they don't miss a beat.
當然了  因為有臉譜網  電郵和博客之類的
Yeah, and with Facebook and e-mail and blogs and stuff
現在要保持聯系要簡單得多
it's much easier to stay in touch.
聽著  我們來做個約定
Look... here, I'll make you a deal.
我保證  從今往后
I promise that, for the rest of our lives,
我每周都會發一段模仿短視頻
I will send one Vine of me doing an impression every week,
Vine: 推特旗下很火的一種六秒視頻分享應用  可分享到各社交網站  并進行互動
然后你可以給我發發擠胸圖神馬的
And then you can send me one of you soaping up your boobs.
老兄
Dude.
這樣不太好哇
Inappropriate.
廝混三年
Three years together,
他總算注意到我的胸了嗎
and he finally notices my boobs?
點贊
Victory!
我們都會是一生的好朋友  我保證
We are all going to be friends for life. I promise.
而且高中時光還沒結束呢  對吧
And we still have some high school left, right?
你知道我要做什么嗎
You know what we need to do?
我沒得和這個地方告別
We need to say good-bye to this place
而且要做華麗壯闊的告別
with some heroism and some drama.
我們要做些驚天動地的大舉動  這樣三十年后
We got to do something so epic that in 30 years time,
我們還能在互相聯系時追憶往昔
we can just call each other up and reminisce about it.
不如把一頭牛偷偷運進學校
I know, let's sneak a cow into school.
我更傾向于留校狂歡夜
I was thinking more like an overnight lock-in.
我會跟學生會溝通
I'll talk to the student council,
讓他們批準我們的想法
and I'll get them to approve it.
聽起來挺危險的  我入伙
Sounds dangerous. I'm in.
真棒  我也參加
Yes! Me, too.
三人圍圈打氣
Three-way show circle?
來來來
Get in there.
天下無敵
A... mazing!
-我剛剛做了驗孕  -怎樣
- I just did the pregnancy stick. - Yeah?
沒懷上
It came up negative.
小艾
Oh, Em.
不用太驚慌
There's no reason to panic.
15%到20%的夫婦
I mean, it takes 15-20% of couples
-要一整年才懷得上孩子  -我知道
- a full year to get pregnant. - I know.
以防萬一  我已經在15號
Look, just in case, I went ahead and made an appointment
提前和婦產科醫生做了預約
at the fertility doctor on the 15th.
我們去醫院  請個事假
And we'll-we'll go, we'll take a personal day,
一起去看看醫生
and we'll both go in together.
我保證  我們會找出原因的
I promise you, we'll figure this out.
抱歉  失陪一下
Uh, I'm-I'm sorry. Excuse me.
威爾  真的很抱歉
Oh, Will, I'm real sorry.
我也不想打岔  威廉  但是
Oh, I don't mean to intrude, William, but, uh,
雖說輪不著我來告訴你
far be it from me to tell you
怎么讓我討厭的那個脆弱神經女懷上孩子
how to inseminate a frail, neurotic woman that I hate,
但我突然想到  你可以試著
but it occurs to me, you might want to try
讓你那神經兮兮的類人猿老婆放松一下
to relax your already mentally fragile ape-wife
而不是對著她大講特講受孕數據
instead of making her cervix snap shut like a barnacle
嚇得她的子宮頸像蛤蜊似的啪嗒一下合上了
by bombarding her with a barrage of pregnancy statistics.
蘇講得有道理  親
Sue's got a point there, hon.
別附和我了
Oh, stop agreeing with me.
你知道你在說什么嗎
You don't know what you're talking about.
我覺得你能生出來的玩意
The only thing I can see you giving birth to
只能是一簍子褐色土豆
is a bushel of russet potatoes.
當邁克爾·波頓讓我懷孕的時候
You know, when Michael Bolton impregnated me,
他找來了老朋友肯尼·基
he called in a favor from his old friend Kenny G,
他就站在我們床尾  用高音薩克斯演奏小夜曲
who stood at the foot of our bed and serenaded us on soprano sax
同時  邁克爾那寬厚圓潤的嗓音
as Michael used every inch of his enormous, silky-smooth vocal range
安撫我深深進入放松狀態
to soothe me into a state of relaxation so deep,
簡直只能用宗教感來形容
it could only be described as religious.
我說真的  威爾
I'm serious, Will.
我簡直比雷諾老虎機還要松
I was looser than a Reno slot machine.
親  妹子發不發情不是重點
Punkin', it don't matter if you got a she-goat in heat.
你還是得讓她平靜下來才能...
You still gotta calm her down before you
辦事
knock her up.
這是我那邊的說法
That's a saying where I come from.
你那邊是哪邊
And where do you come from?
怎么感覺是核廢料場上的度假農場呢
It seems like a dude ranch on a nuclear waste site.
我的意思是
What I mean is,
如果你們準備要懷孕
if you're ready to get pregnant,
就得順其自然
you gotta make it real natural.
你們倆人都不能有壓力
It'll take the pressure off of both of youse.
如果你和艾瑪準備好了要開始嘗試
If you and Emma are ready to start trying,
就得放棄嘗試
you got to stop trying.
麥金利高中的同學們注意了
Attention McKinley students.
我剛剛得到通知  麥金利高中學生會
I have just been informed that the McKinley High Student Council
投票通過了本周末的第一屆年度畢業生留校狂歡夜
has voted to approve the First Annual Senior Lock-In this weekend.
同時也要遺憾地通知你們  我將取消這次活動
And I regret to inform you that I'm cancelling this event,
原因是經費削減  安全隱患
due to budget cuts, safety concerns,
還有什么  就算是奧巴馬醫改吧
and-- oh, I don't know-- let's say Obamacare.
蒂娜  老天  你還好嗎
Oh, Tina-- oh, my gosh, are you okay?
留校狂歡夜被取消了
The lock-in was cancelled!
蒂娜  你為什么這么在意
Oh, Tina, why are you so worried about it?
我們昨天才想到這件事
We just thought of that yesterday.
我知道這會是我們的第一個留校狂歡夜  布萊恩
I know it would have been our first lock-in, Blaine,
但也會是最后一個啊  布萊恩
but it would have been our last lock-in, Blaine,
現在  什么都沒有了
and now, we don't have that at all!
每過去一天
Every day that passes
我們就離永不再見越來越近
is another day closer to never seeing each other ever again!
好了好了  好了好了
Okay, okay, okay, okay, um, uh...
不如這樣  不如
How about this? How about...
不如我們  自己舉辦留校狂歡夜
how about we, um, have our own lock-in?
-就我們三個人  -沒錯
- Just the three of us? - Yeah.
我們要怎么搞定
How would we manage that?
很簡單  我們來這么辦
Easy. Here's what we'll do, okay?
我們從合唱排練室的窗子爬進來
We'll climb in through one of the choir room windows.
到時候留一扇別鎖  沒人會發現的
We'll leave one unlocked, and no one will ever notice.
對  怎么樣  蒂娜  你說呢
Yeah, how about it, Tina? What do you say?
好啦  站起來先
All right. Let's get you up.
-我們先出去  -好
- Let's get you out of here. - Okay.
蒂娜  我很認真地問你
Now, Tina, I've been meaning to ask you.
你的胸變大了嗎
Are your boobs getting bigger?
-可能嗎  -嗯嗯  確實變大了  薩姆
- Is it possible? - Yes. Yes, they are, Sam.
謝謝  你最棒了
Thank you. You're the best.
婦炎潔  我自由了
哈梅爾女士  過來
Lady Hummel, come here.
我需要你纖細優雅又靈巧的手指
I need your tiny, delicate, elfin-like fingers
幫我綁住這條辮子
to help me fasten this weave.
是我  艾略特
It's Elliott, actually.
還有  你頭發真多
And... that's a lot of hair.
-我就當這是夸獎吧  -嗯哼
- I will take that as a compliment. - Okay.
這是我搞瘋貝里宏偉計劃的一部分
It's all a part of my master plan to psyche out Berry
這樣我就能演范妮·布萊斯
so I can play Fanny Brice.
首先來點兒驚艷的新發型
First comes some amazing new hair,
然后是她永遠穿不出感覺的
then, incredibly sexy rehearsal clothes,
超級性感的排練服
which she could never pull off,
然后我會溜進劇院
and then I'm gonna sneak into the theatre
把她高一時候的年鑒照片釘在墻上
and tack up yearbook photos of her from sophomore year,
她那時候是個笨拙的小胖子  主要為了提醒她
when she was a chunky little butterball, just to remind her--
一朝肥  永生肥
hey, once a fatty, always a fatty.
上帝為證  我會打倒她的
God as my witness, I will break her down.
妹子  這也太高中了
Oh, girl, this is so high school.
人生就是這么高中  只是玩得更大票而已
Okay, life is very high school, just with bigger stakes,
如果你像我們這么了解貝里
and if you knew Berry the way that all of us did,
你就會為我鼓掌
you would be applauding me.
開始一切都陽光燦爛  風平浪靜
In the beginning, it's all sunshine and giggles and stickers,
但是  只要你和她追求一致
and then, the second that you want the same thing as her,
她那毛茸茸的小下巴上就升起一片烏云
a dark cloud comes over her whiskery little chin.
她會把你吃光抹凈  再吐出來
And she will chew you up and spit you out,
簡直就是猶太版希拉里·克林頓
like a Jewish Hillary Clinton.
要知道  我只是來拿她的樂譜的
You know, I... I'm actually just here to get her sheet music.
-你知道她放哪兒了嗎  -她屁股上
- Do you know where she keeps it? - Up her butt.
說真的  她讓我過來取
Seriously. She asked me to come here and pick it up,
而且  她就要搬進我的公寓了
and, you know, she's moving into my apartment.
等等  你剛剛說什么
Wait. Wh-Wh-What did you just say?!
你怎么能這樣對我  真是個大叛徒
How could you do this to me? You are such a traitor!
首先我幾乎不認識你  所以也不算什么叛徒
A, I hardly know you, so I'm not really being a traitor.
其次  她需要住的地方  我需要錢
And B, she needed a place to stay, and I needed the money.
-你需要錢嗎  -對啊
- You need money? - Well, yeah.
也許辣手摧花姐能幫你這個忙
Huh. Well, maybe Auntie Snixx could help you out with that.
在這個即將畢業的時節里
In a world on the verge of graduation,
有一位英雄挺身而出  對抗邪惡
one hero stands against evil.
那就是我  黑羽
I, the Dark Feather.
加油  加油
Come on. Come on.
夜鶯
Nightbird.
你真是把簡單事情復雜化了
Okay, you made this way more difficult than it needed to be?
此槽不吐不快
Just for the record.
你有必要穿成這樣嗎
Any excuse to put on that costume.
這是我最后一次有機會穿了
Well, it's the last chance I get to put it on,
除非我去什么奇葩的戀物俱樂部
unless I'm in some kind of creepy fetish club.
-你們聽到了嗎  -聽到什么
- Shh. Did you guys hear that? - Hear what?
偉大畢業生留校狂歡夜開始的聲音
Sound of an epic senior lock-in about to start?
*常來看看我*
*Won't you come see about me*
*你懂無人共舞的寂寞*
*I'll be alone, dancing you know it baby*
*生活的煩惱跟我說說*
*Tell me your troubles and doubts*
*詳細的情況向我談談*
*Giving me everything inside and out and*
*情誼生分  黑暗中格外真實*
*Love's strange so real in the dark*
*想想我們在解決的棘手事情*
*Think of the tender things that we were working on*
*細微的改變將我們分離*
*Slow change may pull us apart*
*當光線射入你的內心*
*When the light gets into your heart, baby*
太抑郁  無心打開小冊子
*勿忘我*
*Don't You Forget About Me*
例假來了  還是被槍擊了
*勿  忘  我*
*Don't Don't Don't Don't*
太抑郁  不敢打開小冊子
例假來了  還是中彈流血
*勿忘我*
*Don't You Forget About Me*
安全性行為  請用避孕套
*你我擦肩而過*
*As you walk on by*
*你會喚我名嗎*
*Will you call my name*
*你我擦肩而過*
*As you walk on by*
*你會喚我名嗎*
*Will you call my name*
*你我擦肩而過*
*When you walk away*
*喚我名  喚我名*
*Come on, call my name*
*你會喚我名嗎*
*Will you call my name*
*喚我名  喚我名*
*Come on, come on*
*喚我名*
*Call my name*
*你還能喚我名*
*You can call my name*
捉住了
Busted!
你們死在我手上了
Your fat asses are mine.
開始狂歡吧
Let's get this party started!
11小時能量飲料  人人有份
11-hour energies for everybody!
我們不想顯得太粗魯  但是
Uh, we don't want to be rude, but...
我聽不見  小常常
I can't hear you, Chang-Chang!
我正忙著喝11小時能量飲料呢
I'm too busy drinkin' my 11-hour energies!
太爽了  寶貝
Oh, yeah, baby!
難道不覺得你該
Don't you think you need to slow down a little bit
慢點喝能量飲料嗎  貝基
on the energy drinks there, Becky?
還有啊  你是怎么進來的
By the way, how did you even get in here?
我從窗戶爬進來的  呆子
I climbed through the window, fool!
扭扭樂時間到
It's time for Twister!
只要跌倒  就喝一瓶這個
Every time you fall down, you drink one of these.
貝基  我們會死的
Becky, we'll die.
美帝派對開始
Party in the U.S.A.!
好吧  聽起來很有趣
All right, that-that sounds really fun,
但我們覺得
um, but we were thinking that
今晚還是按原計劃好了
we would just do our own thing tonight.
請三思  基友布萊恩
Think again, Gay Blaine!
如果你們不跟我玩扭扭樂
If you don't play Twister with me,
我就報警
I'm calling the cops.
傻眼了吧
Oh, snap!
工藝室怎么成這樣了
What did you do to the craft room?
終于把這房間清理出來了
Finally cleared it all out.
這里唯一會有的一件藝術品
You know, the only work of art that belongs in here
將是我們倆一起創造的
is the one we're gonna make together.
等等  你在裝修育兒室嗎
Wait, are you setting up the nursery?
這會帶來厄運  我還沒懷孕呢
Well, that's bad luck. We haven't even conceived yet.
你擔心太多了
You worry too much.
你才知道嗎
You're just figuring that out now?
我們都太瞻前顧后
We both worry too much.
我沒有遠大志向  艾瑪
My dreams aren't big, Emma.
我不想登月
I don't want to go to the moon
也不想成為紅人隊的三壘手
or play third base for the Reds.
我只想當藝術老師
I just want to teach art to kids
和我的夢中人有個美滿的家庭
and have a family with the girl of my dreams.
你的夢中人應該能生育
The girl of your dreams probably has a more fertile womb.
所有的醫生都說沒問題
Hey, all the doctors said that everything was fine
我們倆都沒事
for both of us.
我們只要放松  好好享受
We just need to relax and enjoy this.
我們都太怕讓對方失望
We're so afraid of letting each other down
整個家滿滿都是恐懼
that-that all there is in our home is fear.
什么樣的寶寶愿意出生在這樣的家里
What baby's going to want to be born into that space?
反正我的寶寶不會
Not mine.
我好愛你
I love you so much.
我也愛你
I love you, too.
那么我們就一起享受
Then let's just enjoy the fact
終于遇到人生摯愛的快樂
that we finally found our one and only true loves
靜候某位魔力小天使
and see what magical little spirit wants to come along
加入我們的生活
and join us for the ride.
愿意幫把手嗎
Mind giving me a hand?
愿意
Okay.
*人們笑著說我是個幸運的男子*
*People smile and tell me I'm the lucky one*
*我們的幸福剛剛開始*
*And we've only just begun*
*我想我就要有個兒子*
*Think I'm gonna have a son*
*像他的父母  鴿子般自由自在*
*He will be like she and me, as free as a dove*
*身邊滿是慈愛*
*Conceived in love*
*太陽對他笑顏開*
*Sun is gonna shine above*
*即使我們身無分文*
*And even though we ain't got money*
*親愛的  我愛你至深*
*I'm so in love with you, honey*
干闥婆  印度神話中的司樂天神
*一切用愛鏈接起來*
*And everything will bring a chain of love*
*每天早晨醒來的時候*
*And in the morning, when I rise*
*你都讓我幸福地淚流*
*You bring a tear of joy to my eyes*
*你說一切都會如我們所求*
*And tell me everything is gonna be alright*
*雙魚  處女上升是個好兆頭*
*Pisces, Virgo rising is a very good sign*
*堅強而又寬厚*
*Strong and kind*
*這個孩子為我所有*
*And the little boy is mine*
*現在我看到了嶄新的一家*
*Now I see a family where the once was none*
*我們剛剛開始啊*
*Now we've just begun*
*朝著太陽飛翔吧*
*Yeah, we're gonna fly to the sun*
*即使我們身無分文*
*And even though we ain't got money*
*親愛的  我愛你至深*
*I'm so in love with you, honey*
*一切用愛鏈接起來*
*And everything will bring a chain of love*
*每天早晨醒來的時候*
*And in the morning, when I rise*
*你都讓我幸福地淚流*
*You bring a tear of joy to my eyes*
*你說一切都會如我們所求*
*And tell me everything is gonna be alright*
*一切都會如我們所求*
* Everything is gonna be alright*
-性感小帥哥你好啊  -你好
- Hi, hot stuff. - Hi.
你又輸了
You lose again!
中場休息
Time-out.
我腿有點抽筋
I-I'm getting a cramp in my leg.
薩姆和蒂娜離開多久了
How long have Sam and Tina been gone?
誰管他們
Oh, who cares?
蒂娜無聊透頂
Tina is boring.
我討厭薩姆的發型
I hate Sam's haircut.
讓他的腦門顯得巨大無比
It makes his forehead look too big.
我要到處走走  緩解抽筋
You know what? I'm gonna... walk this cramp off.
好吧
Okay.
我會一直等你回來呦
When you come back, I'll be here.
我會多喝幾瓶功能飲料的
I can have some more energy drinks.
薩姆
Sam?
蒂娜
Tina?
我去  你們在做什么
Oh! What the hell are you doing?!
-什么都  -沒做
- Uh, nothing! - Nothing!
薩姆  你還記得佩妮小護士嗎
What about Nurse Penny, Sam?
你就把她忘了嗎
What, did you just forget about her?
蒂娜  你簡直...
And, Tina, you're just, ugh!
-不忍直視  -抱歉  都是功能飲料作怪
- Oh, I can't! - I'm sorry, it was the 11-hour energies!
還有莫名的離愁別緒
And cheap, sordid nostalgia.
這本該是我們的夜晚
This was supposed to be our night.
我們這個小家庭
Our little family,
我們友情三人組
our friendly threesome.
這是我們最后在一起的機會  而你們...
It was our last chance to hang out together, and you...
都被你們毀了
you ruined it.
實際上  都怪貝基和她的扭扭樂
Actually, that was Becky! With her Twister!
布萊恩  快回來
Blaine, come back!
-蕾切爾  你遲到了 -抱歉  我在試裝
- Rachel, you're late! - I'm sorry, I was at a fitting.
五號桌  他們等你很久了
Table Five-- they've been waiting for you.
好戲開始了
Well, here we go.
-蕾切爾  -這什么狀況
- Hi, Rachel. - What's going on here?
怎么回事  我們說好要聯手抵制她的
What's going on here? We have a fatwa against her, remember?
我在和艾略特對臺詞
Actually, I am paying Elliot to run lines with me,
等你悲劇地出了意外
and they are going to be letter-perfect
凄慘地靠邊站時
by the time you have the tragic accident
我就能完美地登臺演出了
that sidelines you and leaves you horribly disfigured.
這情況是不是已經發生了  我已經...
Or did that already happen? I can't...
說了幾萬遍
Okay, for the millionth time,
這種情況絕對  絕對不會發生
that is never, ever going to happen.
我把房子讓你了  科特也讓給你了
I gave you the apartment, I gave you Kurt,
我再重復一遍
and you are never-- let me repeat--
你絕對不可能出演這個角色  毫無可能
ever gonna play this part. Ever, okay?
但你不能把我的新朋友也拐走
But you can't take my new best friend.
他又不是你的  蕾切爾
You don't own him, Rachel.
才不跟你說話  叛徒
I'm not speaking to you, traitor!
蕾切爾  三號桌要點歌
Rachel, Table Three is requesting a number.
這對夫妻每年都來這里
The husband and his wife have been coming here every year
為妻子慶生
for the wife's birthday.
妻子名叫葛洛麗亞
Her name is Gloria,
她要求點一首特定的歌
and she requested a certain song be performed.
生日歌嗎
"Happy Birthday"?
羅拉·布蘭妮根的《葛洛麗亞》
"Gloria" by Laura Branigan.
既然是這樣  羅尼  雖然我下班了
Okay, well, Ronnie, in that case, even though I'm off duty,
我愿意來主唱這首歌
I think I'll take the lead on this one,
很明顯蕾切爾唱不了這首歌
since Rachel obviously couldn't handle that song.
來吧  親親  跟我一起唱
Come on, bestie, back me up.
要不你跟我們倆一起唱
Oh, you know, why don't you back both of us up,
最后  你來判斷我們倆誰更好
and then at the end you can decide which one of us is better.
*葛洛麗亞  總是在奔跑*
*Gloria, you're always on the run now*
*追逐別人  總會追上的*
*Running after somebody, you gotta get him somehow*
*你得放慢腳步  否則會出岔*
*I think you've got to slow down before you start to blow it*
*前路盡是心碎  千萬別表露*
*I think you're headed for a breakdown, so be careful not to show it*
*真心不記得  那不正是他說的話嗎*
*You really don't remember, was it something that he said?*
*腦中的聲音  不在呼叫葛洛麗亞嗎*
*Are the voices in your head calling Gloria?*
*葛洛麗亞啊  難道你不正在墜落嗎*
*Gloria, don't you think you're fallin'?*
*如果人人需要你  緣何無人呼叫你*
*If everybody wants you, why isn't anybody callin'?*
*不用回答*
*You don't have to answer*
*就讓他們  一直呼叫葛洛麗亞*
*Leave them hangin' on the li-ine, oh-oh-oh, calling Gloria*
*葛洛麗亞  他們有你的號碼*
*Gloria (Gloria), I think they got your number (Gloria)*
*我總覺得  他們知道你外號*
*I think they got your alias (Gloria) *
*這正是你  一直偽裝的源頭*
*That you've been living under (Gloria)*
*但你不記得  那不正是他說的話嗎*
*But you really don't remember (was it something that they said?)*
*腦中的聲音  不在呼叫葛洛麗亞嗎*
*Are the voices in your head calling Gloria?*
*葛洛麗亞  哦葛洛麗亞*
*Gloria! Ooh Gloria!*
*葛洛麗亞*
*Gloria!*
*葛洛麗亞  他們有你的號碼*
*Gloria! I think they got your number*
*葛洛麗亞  葛洛麗亞*
*Gloria! Gloria! *
*葛洛麗亞*
*Gloria!*
*葛洛麗亞  葛洛麗亞*
*Gloria! Gloria!*
*葛洛麗亞  他們有  有你號碼*
*Gloria! They gotcha, they gotcha number!*
*葛洛麗亞*
*Gloria!*
好吧  星仔
All right, Starchild,
到了一次性解決問題的時候了
it is time to settle this once and for all.
-誰更好  -你們倆都很美
- Who was better? - You're both pretty... and...
我才不會選陣營  或是有偏好
I'm not gonna pick sides or choose favorites or anything...
有時候  你不得不選
Yeah, well, sometimes you have to.
也許是  但不是我  也不是為這事
Well, maybe, but not me, and not for this.
你們倆把問題矛盾解決之前
You know what, until you guys can figure out your stuff,
-我受夠了  我退隊  -什么
- I'm done. I'm done with the band. - What?
桑塔納  你可以重新去找唱歌搭檔
You know what, Santana? You can find a new singing partner.
蕾切爾  你還是我的室友
Rachel, you can be my roommate,
- 但我不是你的新gay蜜  -該
- but I'm not your new best gay. - Ha!
科特  你大概習慣了這種爭執
And, Kurt, you might be used to this kind of drama,
可我受不了
but I'm not.
哥不奉陪了
I'm over it.
布萊恩  等等
Blaine, come on, wait up.
我無法直視你們倆
I can't even look at either of you,
我被你們惡心到了
that's how grossed out I am.
別走了  我們應該向你道歉
Please stop. We owe you an apology.
沒錯  這次留校狂歡夜的意義
Yes, yes, you do. The whole point of this lock-in
在于我們三個人一起玩耍
was for the three of us to have fun together.
而你們倆偷溜了  變成二人世界
Instead, the two of you run off and make it about yourselves
兩個人在那親熱  惡心地談論大胸
with your making out and your gross boob talk.
布萊恩  薩姆和我只是想發泄一下能量
Blaine, Sam and I just needed to get it out of our system.
沒錯  我們是親熱了  當時覺得很熱
Yeah, we tried making out and it was hot and everything,
但我們決定不會在一起
but we decided that we both don't want to be a couple.
沒錯  我們只是想試試各種可能性
Exactly. We just needed to explore the possibility,
現在沒事了
and now it's over.
-只是一場愚蠢的沖動  -就是這樣
- It was a silly senior fling. - That's right.
現在我恢復正常了  蒂娜一點都不迷人
Now I'm back to finding Tina not attractive again, okay?
你看  蒂娜和我  我們不想成為雙人組
So, look, Tina and I, we don't want to be a duet;
我們希望回到三人行  我們三個一起
we want to be a trio again, the three of us.
要不我們三個今晚聚在一起
Why don't the three of us hang out tonight,
不玩扭扭樂  不親熱  也沒有貝基搗亂
no Twister, no making out, no Becky.
不行  我們試過了  你們倆毀了這一切
No. We tried that, and you ruined it.
凱蒂阿蒂約我去保齡球館  我都推掉了
You know, I turned down bumper bowling with Kitty and Artie--
你們知道我有多喜歡保齡球
and you know how much I love bumper bowling--
我拒絕的原因是
I turned it down because I figured
我知道他們倆會一直在那卿卿我我
they were just gonna make out the whole time,
而我不想當電燈泡[第三只輪子]
and I didn't want to be a third wheel.
-是第五只輪子  -結果你瞧
- Fifth wheel. - And then, lo and behold,
在我們的惡作劇之夜
the two of you run off during our fun night of
你們倆偷跑
shenanigans and mischief,
然后變成了惡心的啃臉泄欲之夜
and you turn it into some kind of creepy face-sucking slurp-a-thon
現在那畫面還在我腦子里  揮之不去
which I still can't get out of my head!
所以我想今晚還是你們倆玩吧
So I guess you guys can just have fun
慢慢享受
hanging out by yourselves tonight
相互摸胸之類的  愛怎樣怎樣
and... fondle each other's boobs, or whatever.
你想這樣嗎
I mean... do you want to?
和平座談是沒有意義的  科特
There's no point in trying to broker the peace, Kurt.
-我沒興趣  -我也沒有
- I am not interested. - Neither am I.
不過  如果你能讓我們自行解決
Although, if you can clear out some space for us here,
我倒是很樂意用利馬高地的方式解決這場爭端
I would be happy to settle this Lima Heights style.
一山不容二虎
Two men enter, one man leaves.
我再給你們倆一次機會
Okay, I'm gonna give you both one more chance
別犯蠢了  成熟點吧
to put the stupidity aside and act like adults.
我就是這種感受  科特
Okay, my feelings are my feelings, Kurt,
就算桑塔納道歉
and they're not gonna change,
我的感受仍然不會變
even if Santana admits that she was wrong.
是你毀了這一切
You broke this.
也許我會毀掉某些東西
I'm gonna broke something,
-但你真是  -都是你的錯
- but you are literally  - You broke it.
我見過的最自私的賤人
the most selfish bitch I've ever met.
我們彼此承諾過
Okay, we promised each other
這兩年會相互支持
that we would stick by each other for two years,
你們倆都沒堅持到兩個月
and you guys haven't lasted for two months,
因為你們除了自己  誰都不在乎了
because you don't care about anyone but yourselves.
那我怎么辦
How about me?
那我的室友也沒有了啊
How about the fact that I lost my roommates, huh?
或是你們嚇到艾略特
Or the fact that you scared off Elliott
他現在要退出樂隊了
and now he wants to quit the band?
這跟樂隊沒關系  好嗎  科特
This has nothing to do with the band, Kurt, okay?
-桑塔納和我都是專業的  -沒錯
- Santana and I are both professionals. - Exactly.
眨眼182的成員相互討厭
Blink 182 hated each other
仍然在一個樂隊里合作多年
and still found a way to continue to suck as a band for years.
你們倆別擔心樂隊了
Oh, you know, you guys don't have to worry about the band,
你們倆被踢出去了
because you're out.
-什么  -帕米拉·蘭斯伯里樂隊解散了
- What?! - Pamela Lansbury is dead.
我  艾略特和丹妮重建一支新樂隊
I'm starting a new band with Elliott and Danny.
是個三人合唱組
It's gonna be a trio.
等等  我女朋友也同意
Okay, wait, so my own girlfriend agreed
把我開除嗎
to kick me out of the band?
你女朋友想好好唱歌  享受樂趣
Your girlfriend wants to sing and have fun,
她清楚如果你還呆在樂隊  就是不可能的
and she knows that's impossible with you still in the band.
這是我們首秀的宣傳單
Okay, here is a flyer for our first gig.
希望你們倆能消停一會
I hope the two of you can declare an armistice
帕米拉·蘭斯伯里解散  新合唱三人組誕生
科特·哈梅爾  艾略特·吉爾伯特及丹妮  周五晚  復試酒吧
來看我們的演出
long enough to come and watch us play.
謝謝邀請  科特
Thank you, Kurt.
桑塔納  我希望你能克服一下
Well, Santana, I hope that you can rise above,
因為我絕對不會錯過演出
because I wouldn't miss it for the world.
好吧  請自覺待在酒吧的另一邊  矮子
Okay, well, just make sure that you stay on your side of the club, dwarf.
我剛看到一只松鼠從你頭發后面鉆出來
I think I saw a squirrel come out of the back of your hair.
依我看來  咱們現在有兩種選擇
Okay, look, the way I see it is we have two options right now.
第一  我們可以在這間酒吧里
One, we can have an all-out catfight
火力全開  大干一架
right here in the middle of this bar...
-贏的肯定是我  -第二
- Which I would win. - Or...
看在科特的面子上  我們可以假裝是朋友
for the sake of Kurt, we could just pretend to be friends,
-即便只此一晚  -好吧
- even if it's just for tonight. - Fine.
不過只此一晚
But just for tonight,
而且只是以為我不想濺得滿身是血
and only because I don't want to get your blood all over my outfit.
大家好
Hello, everybody.
我是科特  歡迎光臨
I'm Kurt, and welcome.
我知道你們大多數人很期待
I know most of you were excited to see
帕米拉·蘭斯伯里今晚的演出
Pamela Lansbury perform tonight,
但可惜的是  我要宣布一個壞消息
but unfortunately, I have some sad news.
帕米拉·蘭斯伯里  解散了
Pamela Lansbury... c'est fini.
-什么  -對  但別擔心
- What?! - Yeah, but do not worry,
因為我們猶如涅槃重生般
because rising from the ashes like a phoenix,
組建了一支新紐約合唱三人組
I give you New York's new singing thruple--
三季樂團
One Three Hill!
謝謝
Thank you.
如果一年前  有人問我
Uh, you know, a year ago, had someone asked me
是否想加入合唱三人組
if I thought I'd ever be a part of a singing trio,
我肯定會說想
I would have said absolutely.
可能不是現在的成員組合
Maybe not this combination exactly,
盡管他們都很優秀
as amazing as they are,
-別說廢話趕緊唱吧  -但正如常言道
- Shut up and sing! - But, uh... I guess it's like what they say.
人生之路漫長而崎嶇
Life is one long and windy road,
你永遠無法預知未來如何
and you're never sure what might happen.
而下面這首歌說的就是這個
Speaking of which...
*嘿生活  瞧瞧我*
*Hey, life, look at me*
*我可以洞察真實*  *天有不測風云*
*I can see the reality* *Beware of The Happening*
*每當你動搖顛覆我的世界*
*'Cause when you shook me, took me outta my world*
*我驚醒*
*I woke up*
*恍然大悟*
*Suddenly I just woke up*
*意外人生*
*To The Happening*
*某日醒來*
*One day you're up (One day you're up)*
*驀然回首*
*Then you turn around (When you turn around)*
*你的世界*
*You find your world (You find your world)*
*已分崩離析*  *萬劫不復*
*Is tumbling down* *Is comin' down*
*我曾深陷其中  你也難逃厄運*
*It happened to me, and it can happen to you*
*曾確定  安全無虞*
*I was sure, I felt secure*
*誰知遇到愛轉角*  *天有不測風云*
*Until love took a detour* *Beware of The Happening*
*站在世界之巔正自鳴得意*
*Yeah! I'm riding high on top of the world*
*忽然間*
*It happened*
*天外飛來橫禍*
*Suddenly it just happened*
*突如其來*
*The Happening*
*看清人生*
*Now I see life (Now I see life)*
*真實為何*
*For what it is (For what it is)*
*不為夢想*
*It's not of dreams (It's not of dreams)*
*不為福祉*
*It's not of bliss (It's not of bliss)*
*我曾深陷其中  你也難逃厄運*  *曾幾何時*
*It happened to me and it can happen to you* *Once*
*不測風云*  *瞬間而至*
*And then it happened* *And then it happened*
*Oo, and then it happened* *Oh, it happened*
*是真  或是假*
*Is it real? Is it fake*
*如戲人生皆是錯*  *天有不測風云*
*Is this game of life a mistake* *Beware of The Happening*
*失去心中篤定的摯愛*
*'Cause when I lost the love I thought was mine*
*無法挽回*
*For certain*
*突然悲傷溢滿胸懷*
*Suddenly I start hurtin'*
*意外人生*
*The Happening*
*曾經  安全無虞*
*So sure, I felt secure*
*誰知遇到愛轉角*  *天有不測風云*
*Until love took a detour* *Beware of The Happening*
*柔情蜜意心中漾*
*'Cause when you got a tender love you don't*
*無所顧忌*
*Take care of*
*你最好開始小心*
*Then you better beware of*
*意外橫生*
*The Happening*
天吶  真惡心
Oh, my God. Gross.
你翻我的內褲抽屜干什么  臭拉拉
Why are you digging through my panty drawer, lezzie?
因為在這個抽屜塞滿丁字褲
Well, because before this drawer was filled
和脫衣舞娘胸罩之前
with crotchless panties and stripper bras-- ah--
里面裝的是我的香熏蠟燭
it was my scented candle drawer.
艾略特人不錯  但他貌似只會
Elliott's lovely but he seems to only know
用小茴香和咖喱燒飯
how to cook with cumin and curry.
我們能否聊一下
Okay, can we just talk for a second about
你以前用整個抽屜來裝香薰蠟燭的事吧
how you used to have an entire drawer dedicated to scented candles?
等下次吧
Maybe another time.
有意思的是  我發現
You know, it's funny, but I realized that
我在紐約沒有其他女性朋友
I really don't have any other girl friends here in New York City,
你是我僅有的一位
and you were sort of my only one.
那你應該由此意識到
Well, maybe you should take that as a sign
自己有嚴重的人格障礙
of your horrible personality disorder.
不好意思  我也沒看見你滿城轉悠
I'm sorry, but I don't see you perusing around town
跟女性朋友把酒言歡啊
having cocktails with any of your gal pals.
好吧  我們在高中大概沒什么女性朋友
Okay. I guess we didn't have a lot of girl friends in high school.
布里特妮不算數  因為我愛她
Brittany doesn't count 'cause I was in love with her.
雖說我還有奎恩
And I guess I had Quinn but...
不過她現在離我只有一小時路程
the fact that she lives an hour away
但我卻從沒想過給她打電話  這就很能說明問題了
and I never thought about calling her should say something to me.
是啊  可惜我們當時只顧著搶男人和獨唱去了
Yeah. Sucks that we were all so competitive about boys and solos.
雖說科特和艾略特很棒
I mean, you know, Kurt and Elliott are great,
但能有個懂你的人在身邊還是不一樣
but it's just different having someone who really gets it.
我就不明白了  為什么是我的角色
I just don't understand. Like, why my part?
為何要做我的替角
Why my understudy?
我遇此良機  就順勢抓住了
There was an opportunity and I took it.
換做你也會這么干
You would have done the same thing,
然后你也會努力干掉擋道的那個人
and then you would have fought to take down whoever was in your way.
即使對方是我
Even if it was me.
在紐約  要杯黑咖啡...
In New York City, ask for a black coffee...
你們倆共處一室  還都毫發無損
Well, you two in the same room and there are no stitches?
-真是種進步  -我們正準備排練
- That's an improvement. - We were just gonna rehearse.
科特挑了一首超棒的三重唱曲目
Uh, Kurt picked out the best trio song ever.
-我正準備走  -我也得走了
- I was just leaving. - Yeah, I'm gonna go, too.
別走  親愛的  留下吧
No, no, no, babe, stay.
我之前同意科特把你踢出樂隊
It'll make me feel less guilty
你留下的話我心里會沒那么內疚
about being okay with Kurt kicking you out of the band.
我得去上班
I have to go to work.
正式聲明  我覺得你們倆都很棒
Hey, for the record, I think you guys are both amazing.
如果你們倆將來和好
If you manage to patch things up at some point,
我很樂意跟你們任何一個人合唱  或者...
I would love to sing with either of you or...
做咖喱給你們吃
cook some curry.
我們都會的
We all would.
好吧  我覺得最近是不太可能了
Right, well, I don't really see that happening any time soon,
我得去排練了
and I have to go to rehearsal.
-失陪  -你是個叛徒
- Excuse me. - You're a traitor.
再見
Bye.
我還以為你要從窗戶爬進來呢
So, I thought you were gonna climb in through the window.
我以后不打算穿斗篷了
I think I'm retiring my cape.
看來你在不少事情上變成熟了
Guess you're outgrowing a lot of things.
不  我當時氣瘋了
No, I freaked out.
我錯了  對不起
And I was wrong and I'm sorry.
我本以為高四這年會過得很完美
I thought we were gonna have the perfect senior year,
但卻發生了各種怪事  過得無比艱難
and the one that we got has been so weird and really hard.
-是啊  -所以當我策劃了一次完美的活動
- Yeah. - And so when I tried to plan the perfect night out
但卻沒按照我事先的想法進行時  我就失控了
and it didn't go the way that... that I'd hoped, I-I flipped out.
大概是看到我從未想過會接吻的
And I guess I found it shocking to find two people kissing
兩個人在接吻  我太震驚了
that I never really expected to find kissing,
但這種事在我們身邊經常發生
but, really, that happens all the time around here.
-沒錯  -對  -你說得對  蒂娜
- It does. - Yeah. - You were right, Tina.
一切都在改變
Everything is changing,
我能理解你想在一切永遠改變之前做各種嘗試
and I get why you want to try everything before it changes for good.
但我能向你保證有件事不會變
But the one thing I can promise is not gonna change
那就是我們永遠都是朋友
is that we are gonna be friends forever.
這話我喜歡
I like the sound of that.
抱歉  伙計們
I'm sorry, guys.
你們覺得我們畢業之后這里會變成什么樣
What do you all think's gonna happen to this place when we leave?
到時候合唱團大概就剩三個孩子了
I mean, there's only gonna be, like, three kids in the glee club.
一想到合唱團少了我們就感覺很奇怪
It feels so weird to think about Glee Club going on without us.
至少我們可以
Well, at least we can leave them
再給他們留一座全國賽獎杯做紀念
with a second national championship to remember us with.
-真惡心  -阿蒂  你想跟我們一起嗎
- Meenage-a-gross. - Hey, Artie, uh, you want to join us?
我們正在搞高四真情告白
We're just having, like, a little senior moment if you want to,
你可以過來參加
you know, take part.
不用了  我可不想打擾你們的強勢三人組
No, I don't want to interrupt your power trio.
好了
All right, all right, all right, all right!
All right.
過來
Come on.
好了
Okay!
各位同學們
Ladies and gentlemen,
還有一周就到全國賽了
one week until nationals.
我本打算訂晚餐過來吃
Okay, I was planning on ordering dinner in
跟你們排練到深夜  但我后來意識到
and working you guys deep into the night, but then I realized
太糾結于自己想要的東西
that worrying too much about what you're trying to accomplish
反而會適得其反
actually gets in the way of what you're trying to accomplish.
作為帶出過全國賽冠軍的導師
And as a coach who knows what a national championship team looks like,
我得說
I have to say...
你們已經準備好了
...you guys are ready.
愛你
Love you!
除了一件事
Except for one thing.
別忘帶防曬霜
Don't forget your sunblock
因為下周的這個時候
because this time next week,
我們就要去陽光普照的洛杉磯了
we are gonna be in sunny Los Angeles.
等等  舒老師  舒老師
Wait, Mr. Shue, Mr. Shue.
對我們畢業生而言  這是最后一次合唱課了
So, for us seniors, this is one of our last Glee Club meetings.
意義重大
It's kind of a big deal.
我們能否唱最后一首歌
We were wondering if we could just do one last number.
好  請吧
Yes, please.
我們想請阿蒂加入我們的三人合唱組
And we wanted to ask Artie to be a part of the trio with us.
如果我沒記錯的話
Yeah, if memory serves,
四重唱的威力要高出百分之二十五
a quartet is 25% more powerful.
我們只是剛剛算過賬來
We're just a little slow at the math.
我說對了
I was right.
*我明白你的痛苦*
*I know this pain*
*為何要這般作繭自縛*
*Why do you lock yourself up in these chains?*
*只有你才是自己生活的主人*
*No one can change your life except for you*
*不要讓人凌駕于你之上*
*Don't ever let anyone step all over you*
*只要你敞開心扉*
*Just open your heart and your mind*
*就能觸摸到真實的內心*
*Is it really fair to feel this way inside?*
*終有一天*
*Some day somebody's*
*你會揮手告別  轉身離開*
*Gonna make you want to turn around and say goodbye*
*但在此之前*
*Until then baby*
*你可以找一個肩膀  痛哭一場*
*Are you going to let them hold you down and make you cry*
*請務必相信  事情終有轉機*
*(Don't you know?) Don't you know things can change*
*你終將心想事成*
*Things'll go your way*
*只要你能再堅持一天*
*If you hold on for one more day*
*只要你能多堅持一天*
*你終將心想事成*
*Things'll go your way*
*再多堅持一天*
*Hold on for one more day*
*你可以忍氣吞聲*
*You could sustain*
*還是已經心甘如怡*
*Or are you comfortable with the pain?*
*所有不幸福  不是別人的錯*
*You've got no one to blame for your unhappiness*
*都是咎由自取的結果*
*You got yourself into your own mess*
*讓煩惱隨風而去*
*Lettin' your worries pass you by*
*親愛的  難道你不覺得*
*Baby, don't you think it's worth your time*
*心意需要改變了嗎*
*To change your mind? (No! no!)*
*終有一天*
*Some day somebody's*
*你會揮手告別  轉身離開*
*Gonna make you want to turn around and say goodbye*
*但在此之前*
*Until then baby*
*你可以找一個肩膀  痛哭一場*
*Are you going to let them hold you down and make you cry*
*請務必相信  事情終有轉機*
*(Don't you know?) Don't you know things can change*
*你終將心想事成*
*Things'll go your way*
*只要你能再堅持一天*
*(If you hold) on for one more day*
*堅持住*
*Hold on*
*再堅持一天*
*Hold on for one more day*
*你終將心想事成*
*Cuz it's gonna go your way*
*多堅持一天*
*Hold on for one more day*
*終會心想事成  只要多再堅持一天*
*Things'll go your way (Things'll go your way)*
*再堅持一天*
*Hold on for one more day*
我們還有兩天就要去洛杉磯了  小艾
We leave for L.A. in two days, Em.
你最好開始收拾行李了
You better start packing.
我知道你喜歡把行李都真空包裝起來
I know how you like to vacuum-pack all your stuff.
我大概不能跟你一起去了
I... I don't think I'm gonna go with you.
你最好去
You better go.
你是我的幸運符
Hey, you're our good luck charm.
再說了
And, besides,
我們不能錯過懷孩子的關鍵一周
we can't miss a prime week of baby-making time.
這個嘛
Well...
如果已經懷上了就沒關系了
we can if one has already been made.
我懷孕了
I'm pregnant.
天吶
Oh, my God.
天吶  天吶
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
太棒了
This is amazing!
等等  你是真懷孕了
Wait, wait, wait. Are-are you really pregnant
還只是假裝懷孕
or are just pretending to be?
上次某人告訴我她懷孕的時候
Because last time somebody told me they were pregnant,
情況很糟糕
it was really bad...
聽我說  醫生已經確認了
Listen, listen-- the doctor confirmed it.
我真的懷上你的孩子了  威爾
I'm really, really pregnant with your baby, Will.
我要為你生寶寶了
I'm gonna have your baby.
天吶
Oh, my God.
我們要組建真正的家庭了
We're gonna be a real family.
就我們三個人
Just the three of us.
我愛死你了
Oh, I love you so much.